Patrick McGuigan

Full-Stack Developer

339.788.1008 // Denver, Colorado

Patrick.McGuigan5@gmail.com // https://www.linkedin.com/in/patrickmcguigan/

I am a software engineer putting organization, functionality and user-friendly style at the heart of what I provide to you or your business. I've always had a passion for technology that works seamlessly, and that is exactly what I provide to my clients with my keen eye for detail and aesthetics. The full-stack applications that I build for you will give your users a great experience with each use.

SKILLS

Front-end // Javascript, jQuery, React, HTML, CSS, SASS

Back-end // Javascript, MongoDB, Node, Express, Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL

PROJECTS

PokéSearch // GitHub

 This front-end application is built with HTML, CSS, Javascript, and jQuery using a third party API. This app allows the user to search the Pokédex-style database to learn information about each Pokémon, and various berries found in the games.

MOODSET // GitHub

This full-stack application was built with Node.js, Mongoose, Express, and EJS.
 The playlist creation application allows users to create, display, update, and delete playlists in which they can upload their own music. The database of music was made possible with the use of Cloudinary.

Infinite Savannah // GitHub

 This full-stack application was built with a MERN stack (MongoDB, Express, React, Node) which allows the user to explore a retro-futuristic skateshop. Each user is able to create, view, edit, and delete items via a user-friendly interface. This was built in a group of two using GitHub with a 4 branch structure.

EXPERIENCE

Sales Advisor // Prime Motor Group // November 2018 - December 2019 //

- Developed long lasting relationships with clients.
- Worked as a team with all departments to ensure a smooth all around process.
- Executed professional sales streams that lead to efficiency and organization.
- Created a pleasant sales atmosphere and experience for all of my clients.

Supervisor, Route Setter // Rock Spot Climbing // 2013-2014 // 2015-2018 //

- Oversaw all gym operations and delegated tasks to employees.
- Prepared team practice itineraries for our B-level climbing team.
- Designed intuitive, and fun climbing routes of all levels, and implemented them onto the climbing surface using proper tools and safety.

EDUCATION

Software Engineering Immersive // General Assembly // Remote
Bachelor of Arts: Graphic Design // Curry College // Boston, Massachusetts